I've been using iron Bull's colored
bumper plates for a few weeks now and
aside from the overall versatility that
bumper plates bring to the table I'm a
big fan of the stainless steel inserts
and the high durometer rating plus these
look beautiful but are there any
durability concerns we're going to talk
about that in a whole lot more today so
stick around and we'll find
[Music]
out
what's up everybody it's Jake you know
where I am the barbin garage gym and
today we're going to be talking about
iron Bulls colored bumper plates in this
video I'm going to tell you everything
there is to know about these plates from
the money some pros and cons most
importantly we're going to talk about
who should or maybe should not make this
purchase now before I do that if you're
not aware we've reviewed a lot of other
bumper plates on barb. comom and we do
in fact have a best list of all of our
top picks you want to check that out all
you got to do is search barbin best
bumper plates it's going to pull right
up for you you can find out for yourself
which ones we like the
[Music]
best okay so I already talked about you
know a couple things that I like about
these bumper plates but you know me I
got to expand on that and I really want
to talk about the versatility bumper
plates in general offer so much more
versatility than your standard metal
plates because you can do your
powerlifting but you can also do your
Olympic weightlifting and CrossFit and
that's just something you really can't
do with metal plates because it's
potentially going to damage your barbell
your flooring surrounding equipment
anything like that so for home gems it
really makes the most sense unless
you're only doing powerlifting of course
it really makes the most sense to go
after some bumper plates like these I
really like the durometer rating too so
if you don't know what a durometer
rating is it's a scale 0 to 100 and it's
going to tell you how hard an object is
and in the case of bumper plates how
much bounce you can expect to happen to
occur whenever you drop them right so
the higher the number the harder they
are the less bounce so these have a
durometer rating of 90 it's really high
it's definitely what you want these are
virgin rubber as well so it's not chome
they're not Chum bumpers so chumb
bumpers for those who don't know they're
going to have a lot of Bounce lower
durometer rating and that could
potentially you know be a cause for
concern for injury and damaging
surrounding equipment anything like that
because of how much bounce they have and
they kind of Bounce away from you so
with these I'm going to show you guys
just a minute you know what I mean by
that but you're going to expect you can
expect a dead balance whenever you drop
these and that's definitely something
that I want and I'm sure a lot of people
look for as well these also range from
10 to 55 lbs so aside from from some
change plates you're covered in all
areas right here with these plates and
that's definitely something that you
want as well plus they're competitively
priced I'm going to dig into pricing in
a second too don't go anywhere but
compared to the rest of the market these
are right around the average price price
tag now there's still a few things I got
to bring to your attention the first
thing is that these are not available as
a full set as of right now now their
black bumper plates are available in
full set so you know maybe not too
distant future they're going to add that
as of right now not available as a full
set you're going to have to go and
purchase your individual Pairs and
sticking with money colored bumpers in
general are more expensive than black
ones so definitely keep that in mind if
you're you know tied on a budget
whatever it is just something you just
like I said keep on your mind right
another thing here just a minute ago I
talked about potential durability
concerns that's not because of the
drometer rating you know these do have
stainless steel inserts I'm not worried
about the structural Integrity I'm not
worried about these tacoing on Me Maybe
the 10 lb plate if you're only loading
up 10 lbs and you drop it that is
probably going to bend over time and
that's the case with every bumper plate
not just these what I'm talking about is
how the rubber right here there's
noticeable seams on this side profile
not every single bumper plate has out
there has that the greens I'm noticing
it more than any other ones and so
really I think this only applies to
dedicated crossfitters and Olympic
weightlifters because you're dropping
the plates repeatedly pretty much your
entire workout so that's really where
that comes into play because you know
over time I don't know how long that's
going to last or take I guess should I
say how long it's going to take for you
know you to notice any wear and hair
where this rubber it basically looks
like where this rubber is it's fused
together a lot of companies you can't
even see that it's almost like they sand
it down or maybe just their process is
different in general so that's where you
kind of run into to some potential
concerns over the course of five years
or more definitely just something worth
noting
though so let's talk about some money
and as I mentioned these are basically
you know standard pricing compared to
every other Fitness company's colored
bumper plates whether you're looking at
Rogue rep G faster living fit really
doesn't matter you know insert name
basically the exact same price now these
are not available in full sets
individually these range from 70 lb for
the 10 lb pair up to 270 for a pair of
55 lb okay so these are going to be more
expensive in the long run as opposed to
purchasing a full set and once again
these are not available in a full set so
while a lot of people do like color
bumpers because there's no thinking
involved when it comes to you know
loading your barbell you just memorize
the color grab it you're good to go it's
not necessarily the most practical
purchase for everybody because they are
more expensive especially since these
are not available as a full set one
thing I forgot to mention is that you do
get free shipping if you spend over 150
bucks which you're definitely going to
have to do if you're purchasing these
colored plates you're wanting to make
the most out of your purchase iron buol
does in fact have full sets available
with their black bumper plates so I
definitely suggest going and checking
those
[Music]
[Applause]
out all right so these plates do in fact
meet iws specs in terms of diameter it's
really nice now the thickness however
obviously you know depends on the actual
weight no no weight plates are uniform
in thickness definitely keep that in
mind but you're not going to know just
by browsing their website how thick
these plates are you're going to have to
measure them all individually just for
reference these 45s are a hair under 3
in thick which is pretty average
compared to any other bumper plate out
there some are a little bit thinner but
it's not like you're getting anything
out of the ordinary right here I really
like these cooed collars basically you
know there's no lip right there that's
really nice in terms of durability
however you know I've I've mentioned it
a couple times the 45s aren't as bad
these almost seem like they've been
sanded down a little bit some parts kind
of stick up but you know with these 35s
and with this 25 down here you can
really see where basically it looks like
they took you know Rubber and just like
fused it together and
personally I'm looking for some plates
that don't have that really you know no
signs of that whatsoever these are going
to be just fine for me you know I'm not
dropping my plates a ton I'm not doing a
whole lot I still do them but I'm not
you know dedicated to CrossFit and
everything like that so that's where it
really becomes a cost for concern as far
as general you know home gym athletes
these are going to hold up just fine for
you and remember it's the big thing here
these have a 90 durometer rating so you
know what I'm going to do will all this
out of the way so hang tight with me
real quick and we're going to do a drop
test compared to some Rogue plates that
have at 88 durometer rating just to see
where we're at all right so as I
mentioned I'm going to compare and do a
little drop test right here with the
iron bu plates and Rogues Echo bumpers
reason I'm doing that is because these
are rated at 88 which is up until now
you the highest rated plates that I've
used in the garage all right so just get
right to it and just kind of see what
we're working with
here see that's a nice dead bounce see
what iron bull is working
with about a little bit less I think
it's it's right on par at least right 88
90 it's not really that big of a
difference but if you are in fact
looking for a pair of colored bumper
plates that do offer that dead bounce
iron bullets got you covered so I think
these are great for anybody building out
a home gym because there is a wide range
of Weights available remember 10 to 55
lbs but also because of the durometer
rating these are Rock Solid you're not
going to have any bounce really at all
to experience whenever you drop your
barbell and that goes a long way for the
durability of your barbell and any
additional equipment that's around you
however these are pretty expensive in
the long run compared to a full set of
black bumper plates and really just
black bumper plates in general and then
if you're a dedicated crossfitter or
Olympic weight lifter as I mentioned
earlier you could have some durability
concerns with the seams that are with
the rubber right
here well that's all I got for y'all
today on iron Bulls colored bumper
plates yes I know some crossfitters and
Olympic weightlifters may have some
durability concerns with the rubber but
I've been impressed with these plates
and I think they could make for a great
addition to your home gym thanks for
hanging out with me y'all I hope this
video was helpful I was able to answer
any questions you may have about these
plates I tell you all the time I'm going
to tell you again stay posted for my
next video but for now head over to Barb
and.com CU we have a full written
article about these plates that I
definitely think you should go and check
out all you got to do is search barbend
Iron bull bumper plate review it's going
to pull right up for you you can go over
every single thing we talked about here
today I'll catch youall next
[Music]
time
he